这是一个火箭驱动的高尔夫球杆
This is a rocket-powered Golf Club
专业高尔夫运动员平均挥杆速度有每小时110英里(177km/h)
Professional golfers have an average swing speed of 110 miles per hour
但使用两发F号的固推，挥杆速度能达到每小时150英里(241km/h)
But using two F sized motors she swings at 150 miles per hour, every time
我通常只会给你们看节目中造的东西的成品
Usually for builds on my channel I just show you guys the final thing
但几乎没怎么讲过整个制作流程是怎样的
and don't really talk about the process of how we got there
但放心，本期视频我们将看到固推神教
But rest assured, today, we will get to see huge drives
哇！
WOAH!
以及慢镜头下高尔夫球击碎玻璃
golf balls shattering glass in super slow-mo
击碎西瓜
pulverized watermelons
还能看到手持版本
and even a handheld version
但我觉得这个作品是一个让大家了解幕后工程设计流程的绝好机会
But this build, I think, is a great chance to pull back the curtain
and demonstrate how the engineering design process actually works
我想为你们传授六点……让我们一步步完成这个作品的“经验教训”
I want to highlight six- "learning opportunities" that led us to this final design
为此，我们需要回到四个月前，我最开始想出这个点子的时候
and to do that, We need to go back in time four months to when I first had the idea
和往常一样，我们从一个很简单的原型开始
And as always we started with a simple prototype
来了解这个想法是否有丝毫的可行性
to see if the concept even had a remote chance of working
但在点火之前，你会注意到我在另一端放了配重
Before we fire it up, you'll notice we have counterweights on the opposite side here
这是为了让重心刚好能在旋转轴上
That's so that the center of mass of the spinning part is on top of the axis of rotation
换句话说，它在旋转轴的位置能刚好保持平衡
In other words, It balances perfectly at the point at which it spins around
如果不这样的话
If you don't do that for something that spins
你的系统就需要克服它在旋转时产生的大量额外的力
it creates a bunch of extra force for your system to deal with
一开始只是震动，但加速之后会越来越难顶
It starts as a small vibration, but then it gets worse and worse as you pick up speed
而我们还要用高速的杆头击球
Since we needed to hit this tiny ball with the head of this club at really high speeds
所以如果不平衡
|if we're not perfectly balanced
那球杆连着平台都会发生震动，那就甭想击球了
the club and the whole platform itself will just be shaking all over the place and we'd never hit it
OK，回到测试部分
OK, back to the test
平台震动的比想象中大
Those stands are shaking more than they should
所以我觉得在实际测试中要继续改进旋转部分的平衡
so we knew we would need to balance the spinning part better for the real test
但至少我们知道它转得还算快，而且没炸
But at least we knew it could go kind of fast and nothing blows up
然后就到了计算机辅助设计的时候了，一般下一步都是这个
And so then it was time for CAD which is always the next step
然后我和我的朋友Ken和Kayla开始切金属造东西了
and then together with my friends, Ken and Kayla, we started cutting metal and making stuff
组装很顺利
Things came together well
于是我们把一个3D打印的固推固定装置粘在了杆头上
so we epoxied a 3d printed motor mount to the top of the driver
然后草草开始了我们第一次实测，安全起见周围用网围了起来
and prepped our first real test by taking one of those easy ups and draping some nets on the side for safety
以防万一发生危险
just in case something went catastrophically wrong
这是我们第二个教训，固推固定装置和杆头粘合的接触面太小
This was our second learning experience, we didn't have enough contact area for epoxying the head to the driver
导致粘合不牢
So it wasn't a strong enough bond
这步就很秀了，我们3D扫描了杆头，重新用CAD设计了新的固定装置
this was tricky because it meant we had to 3d scan the club head which allowed us to CAD up
然后3D打印了一个粘合接触面更大的固推固定装置
and then 3d print a more contoured mount with more contact area for the epoxy
我们还增加了一个固推摆放位，毕竟这能有多危险？
We also took this chance to double the rocket holsters because what could possibly go wrong?
于是我们又去测试新的双发E号固推，一切顺利
So we went to test our new dual rocket set up with two e motors and everything went perfectly
除了球杆掉脑袋的部分
Except for the part where the head snapped off the driver
当我们回看高速录像时我注意到球杆太软了
And when we reviewed the slow-mo footage what we realized was the shaft of the driver is so flexible
导致球杆会变弯，让推力方向产生变化
that it would start to bend and then create really weird thrust vectors for the rockets
从而进一步加剧球杆变弯，这是我们不想看到的
which then just bent the shaft even more. This is not what you want to see
最终超过球杆耐弯折的限度后，杆头就飞出去了
Eventually it succeeded the stress limit of the shaft and the head just came off
所以第三条教训就是要加固球杆
So our third learning opportunity was to stiffen up the club shaft
于是我们拿来C形铝条固定球杆
So we got some aluminum C-channel
里面灌满胶水，效果相当不错
and just dumped a butt ton of epoxy in there and this worked remarkably
你能看出前后区别
Well, you can see the difference here
接着我们拿着它来到了遥远的“发射场”，美丽的加州北部
And so with that we headed out to a very remote shooting location in beautiful, northern, California
终于到啦，开始卸货架设备，但在之前我要先说一个事
So we finally arrived and started to set up but first I have something I wanted to get off my chest
我这个人吧，有一个爱好，就是吧……
so one of the things I like most about me is that I will…
其实这俩人YouTube频道都有700万左右的订阅量 Mark只比Destin多38万
Destin在笑Mark装逼装的太6了
我喜欢找一些不那么知名的YouTuber，在我的节目中帮他们火一把
I like to reach out to lesser known channels and sort of give them a hand out at some exposure on my channel
所以女士们先生们，有请SmarterEveryDay频道的Destin
Which is why today I'm here with Destin in SmarterEveryDay
如果你奇迹般地只知道我却不知道Destin
and if by some miracle you don't know
他那大脑袋都能登上科普类YouTuber里的总统山了
Destin is on the Mount Rushmore of science youtubers
我和他是将近六年的老交情了
we've been friends for almost exactly six years
我记得特清楚是因为他订阅我频道的时候我激动地特意了截图
and I know this because I took a screenshot of the huge moment for me when he subscribed to my channel
当时我还只有一万订阅
when I only had 10,000 subs
他做过的视频讲过有关猫着陆的物理知识，放过纹身时慢放的画面
he's made videos about the physics of cats landing on their feet, tattoos in super slow-mo
还有他第一个视频中讲解了配备内部开放反馈回路的鸡头稳定系统
or the first video I saw of him about how chickens have an internal open feedback loop
which allows them to head track
你要是没看过的话那我可太羡慕你了
if you've never seen his stuff I'm actually jealous
因为你突然有了好几个小时的高质量视频可以看了
because you have so many hours of high-quality viewing in your near future
我爱高尔夫
So I like golf
我爱火箭
I like rockets
-真要整这出吗？-哎呀就……好歹有个开场白吧？-对，就当开场白了
Should we do this? Yeah, let's just... That that was the intro right? That was it. Whatever
然后我们就继续架设备了
so we all continued to set up
有一点我觉得很重要，就是让它尽可能像一个发球区
and something that was important to me was for this to look as natural as possible at a driving range
于是我们给基座加了块草皮
so we added some turf to cover the base plate
把又粗又黑的钢制立柱围了一圈球杆袋
and then dissected a golf bag to cover the sturdy steel column
然后里面插几个球杆，这样看上去帅多了
and then if you add some clubs it looks pretty awesome
不但很稳固，还能灵活旋转
It's incredibly rigid and yet it can still swing freely
我们第四条经验来自于回顾最终测试画面的声音过程中
Our fourth learning experience came from reviewing our final test footage
仔细听会发现球杆转得越来越快
if you listen, the club goes faster and faster with each rotation
通常我们想让球杆在转的最快的时候击球
Naturally we want the club to contact the ball when it's going the fastest
在这个例子里是每秒十圈
which in our case is ten rotations in one second
这意味着我们需要在十分之一秒的时间内把球放在球杆的路径上
that means we somehow need to sneak the ball into the path of the driver in less than 1/10 of a second
或者一次眨眼的1/4
or a quarter of an eyeblink
为了做到此事我做了个气动推杆把球推上去
to accomplish this we have a pneumatic cylinder here that hinges up the tee
它可以检测到何时启动
It knows when to fire
因为在球杆转轴的后面有一个光传感器
because on the back of the shaft there's a light sensor
而中间的圆盘有一个开口在每次旋转时可以让光通过
and this disc has a slit which allows the light to pass through once per rotation
我们把这个信号送到Arduino板上帮我计数
So we send that info to an Arduino over here that counts for us
在15次旋转后
and then after 15 rotations
它使用电磁开关来告知推杆准确伸出的时间
it tells the cylinder the precise moment to fire using a solenoid
然后我用强力胶水把球粘在了白色杆的末端
and then we superglue the ball to the tee
因为这个力非常大，所以首先要保证球固定好，然后再让它能飞出去
because it provides the Goldilocks amount of force to first secure and then release the ball
另外慢动作下的强力胶水看上去很酷炫
plus the superglue looks super dope in slow-mo
一切准备就绪，我们先装两个E号的固推
So now with everything in place we started with two e motors
这是和之前把杆头甩掉的是一个构型
which is a reminder is the same setup that ripped the club head off
3，2，1，走你！
three two, one roll
哪去了？咋回事啊？
Where'd it go? What happened?
液！北鼻！
YEAH, BABY!!
那球飞过那些树了！
不是吧
No way
它起飞了！
这射的太牛逼的
that's a cool shot right there. it is
-老铁这效果不错啊 -简直了都
-Dude this is uh, this is respectable -This is legit
在看了更多的高速镜头后我们发现了一些有趣的事情
After reviewing more of the high-speed footage, we noticed something interesting
哈哈哈这应该配个来回摇摆的音效
The sound effect there is like "doy yoy yoy"
这是Destin找到的一个非常有趣的技术发现
This was an interesting technical observation from Destin
而白色立柱过于柔软也让我们打出了一些很糟糕的几杆，比如这样
and that tee flexibility was causing us to hit some bad shots like this
最显然的解决办法就是让白色立柱更结实一点
The obvious fix is just to make the tee more rigid
这样它弹出的时候就不会乱晃
so that it doesn't over rotate when it pops up
但这有一个问题
But there's a problem with this
都说力会沿着刚性物体传递
There's a saying that force follows stiffness
而对于我们来说白色立柱太结实的话会把大量的力传递过去
and for us a really stiff tee would transfer a bunch of force
并摧毁我们3D打印的弹出机构
and destroy our nice 3d printed pop-up mechanism
想象我手里这坨搓成条的纸就是那个白色立柱，它显然很软
Now imagine this crumpled up piece of paper is the tee which is obviously way less stiff
我们用软橡胶制成的白色立柱优势在于它会像这坨纸一样
Our flexible rubber tee was great because it acted like this piece of paper
无论你多用力打它它都不会传递到下面损伤我们的设备
no matter how hard you hit it the force doesn't get translated down and damage our hardware
于是Ken想到一个更好的主意，把一根绳系在白色立柱末端，另一端钉在地上
So Ken had the brilliant idea of just tying a string to the tee and staking it into the ground
这能防止立柱转动过头，同时绳子在拉紧的时候仍能保持立柱是柔软的
This stopped the over-rotation but everything was still just as flexible when the string pulls tight
球能顺利击出是不是因为它没有过度摇晃啊？
does it make the ball fly off because it's it doesn't doink enough?
想证实这点就要做摇晃测试了
Uh, the only way to test is the doink test
摇晃测试
啊漂亮~的确有一点摇晃
Ah, beautiful there was some doinkage
我觉得这真是个很聪明、很简单改进措施
I just thought this was a really simple clever idea
一次解决了两个问题，而且非常有效
that solved both problems at once and as you can see it worked perfectly
现在准备上双发F型固推
Now we are ready to try a dual F motor
推力是之前折断杆头的E型的两倍
So these deliver about twice as much force to the club
as the e motors that made the head snap off
-而这又让我们有了最后一个、最重要的教训 -3，2，1，走你
-and this provided our final and certainly most poignant learning opportunity. -3 2 1 go
球杆呢？？？
Where's the club
滞空时间
-那……哪树着火了吗？-我靠，虽然我在狂笑但这好像不太好
It's, it's, is the tree on fire?  Wow, like I'm laughing, but that could have been bad
瞧吧，快赶上亚轨道火箭了
There we go, this thing was like sub-orbital dude
-我们有三个U型卡扣，但只用了俩 -对
-So we have three u-bolts and we only used two -Yeah
所以这玩意超出了两个U型卡扣的极限，把它们弄坏了
So I think we'll just max out those and just crank them way down
所以我们知道这个故障点了
now that we know this is a failure point
“所以我们知道这个故障点了”？
Now that we know this is a failure point
这话我听说你八百遍了，每次你都等发生以后才有解决办法
There's several failure points and I hear you say, oh we have a solution for that
工程设计就是这样的嘛！
This is the engineering design process!!
太有意思了
Rather fun
我之前说了，球杆飞出去是因为切太短了，只用了两个U型卡扣固定
Like I mentioned the club that failed was cut too short and was only attached using two u-bolts
我们本以为强度足够提供800磅的向心力
Which we thought would have been enough to support the 800 pound load from centrifugal force
我们的确注意到多次点火测试后橡胶手柄会磨损
We did notice the rubber handle was worn due to so many test fires
而这可能就是本次事故的导火索
which probably initiated the stress concentration leading to the failure
所以接下来的改进就是把球杆改长一点
So our fix was to cut the next club longer
这样我们能拧上三个U型卡扣，并且换上全新的橡胶手柄
so we could use three u-bolts and really crank them down on a fresh rubber handle
这样有了之前六条经验教训
and so with all six of our learnings
现在我们重新尝试最牛逼的双F型固推
now in place we tried the insane double F motors one more time
卷帘门效应
求生欲战术倾斜效应（我瞎编的
挖！
WOAH!!
牛逼！继续飞！
YEAH, BABY!! GO!!
牛的内心毫无波澜
这才是玩高尔夫的正确姿势！
THAT's how you play golf!
这是最好的一发了我的老铁
That's our best one yet! Dude
这感觉就好像你的工程作品真的用在现实生活中一样，真的老铁
Like the crush you get from like an engineering achievement actually working in like. Seriously dude
看那火焰啊！啊爽！
Oh look at the flame. OH yeah!
那球最后飞丢了，所以没法测飞了多远
So we never found these long balls to measure the exact distance
但我自己能把球打280码(256米)，而刚刚那杆比我远多了
But I can drive a ball 280 yards and these were well beyond that
你就看这轨迹，简直要去外太空了
I mean just look at this trajectory straight to outer space
既然之前都射差不多了，该玩玩有意思的了
Now that we've got all the shots we needed it was time to have some real fun
首先是手持版本，使用单发C型固推
We started with a handheld version that was powered by a single C motor
因为再大让我拿着可能就太危险了
because anything more than that would just be way too unsafe for me to hold
牛逼！超过300码(274米)了！
Ni-ice! over 300 yards man!
真的感觉是挥杆更轻松了，不骗你，太爽了
It really did Like make it so much easier to swing I'm not even kidding. Yeah. Yeah
真的，感觉真的不一样
yeah, like it really meant different
-3，2…… -接下来是玻璃，原因嘛……
-3,2… -and then some glass just because…
液！
YEAHH!
接下来是本节目传统艺能——开西瓜
And then keeping with the tradition of my channel some watermelon
-感谢Mark同志使用火箭驱动的高尔夫球杆来开西瓜 -那都不是事
-Thanks for cutting open a watermelon with a rocket-powered golf club Mark. -You're welcome
真的，过去三个月的工程就是为了今天这一刻
Yeah, that's all of this the past three months of work in engineering was just for this
就为了今天能吃这个西瓜
Boils down to this moment just to enjoy this watermelon
当然Mark是为了节目效果，但我们也不会浪费食物的
Yeah, Mark's like trying to make stuff look good, we're not wasting food though
我们不会浪费一丝一毫的努力，就像印第安人和水牛一样
we waste no part of the engineering effort like the great Indians with the buffalo
Destin在他的频道上做了一期视频讲了为何有些球弹得高，有些不会
so Destin made a video on his channel about why some balls bounce high and others don't
而我最开始想法很简单，只要考虑它压缩程度或者有多软就行了
and my first thought was well that's easy just has to do with how compressible or rubbery it is
这个台球非常坚硬
Yet this billiard ball is pretty much completely solid
而这个弹力球则非常柔软，但它们弹起高度却很相似
and this bouncy ball is pretty rubbery and yet they bounce to pretty much the same height
所以还是有些说道的
So it's something else
你也能想象到这对于高尔夫球制造者来说还是很重要的信息
As you can imagine this is a pretty important piece of information for golf ball makers
有很多高尔夫球被击打的牛逼的慢放镜头
so there's lots of amazing slow-mo footage of golf balls being squished in ways that hurt your brain
还有很多今天拍摄的画面
plus way more footage from today's shoot
所以我会在视频说明留下链接
So I will leave a link in the video description
到时候记得看看Destin的其他视频，并订阅他的频道
And while you're there make sure to check out some of his other videos and subscribe to his channel
因为它是典型的、啥都知道的专业人士
because he's just a classy individual and a true professional in every sense of the word
-开拍了吗？ -嗯 -氦我是Mark
-Are you rolling? -Yeah. -Hi, it's me Mark
欢迎点赞投币收藏分享关注转发评论充电一波
如果你想自己造一个火箭球杆
If you want to make your own rocket powered golf club
你可以在我的网站上找到所有CAD文件和部件列表，甚至Arduino代码
You can find all the CAD files and the parts list even the code for the Arduino
网址见下方字幕
on a website I created called MarkRoberbuildinstructions.com
在那个网站你其实能看到我频道很多以前的视频造过的东西的说明
and on that site You'll actually see build instructions for tons of videos from my channel
包括我的工作台，全部免费下载，也感谢我的在Wix.com的朋友
including my workbench and it's all for free and made possible by my friends at Wix.com
而我自己的设计审美很单纯
And my personal design aesthetic is simple and clean
所以我直接找了尽可能接近我想要的效果的模板
So I used a template to get me close to what I wanted
但之后我能在wix.com上随意自定义网页内容
But then I was able to customize it as much as I wanted from there
剩下全是恰饭内容就不翻了，有兴趣建站的自己去wix.com吧
And this is great for me because I get a lot of questions about the builds on this channel
and now I'm able to just point People to one spot
and because Wix is on the ball, it automatically looks amazing on mobile
Plus, it's SEO optimized
If you're looking for people to find your site through Google
and my website is just a simple way to communicate information
but you can make one for your personal brand or
Portfolio or maybe a new website for your business to sell stuff online
Or even book appointments right there
and it's free to sign up to start designing and publishing
plus It's really fun and a little bit addictive
so to flex your creative muscles and to support Wix because they support me
Go to wix.com/go/markrober or just use the link in the video description
Thanks for watching